hello is sticks in this video I'll be
showing you the most OP lasel build
guide in balers Gade 3 so this is going
to be the strongest version you can make
lasel and we're going to keep her a
fighter at the start here so you get the
second win for healing there bonus
action for her fighting style the
defense is a best choice for the plus
one Armor class this is better than all
the other ones although great weapon
fighting can be nice too in this video I
will be showing off different types of
gear that you're going to use throughout
the levels as well as a leveling guide
and some combat tips and tricks and I'll
show off some combat so you can stay
tuned for all of that
now for our ability score strength's
going to be a big one for us however we
can build into dexterity if you want to
use medium armor and focus on using
finesse weapons but strength with a big
two-handed weapon seems to be the best
choice here so maxing strength dexterity
of 14 and Constitution 16 if you're
using the gloves of dexterity you can
dump your dexterity and put those points
into wisdom because wisdom saves are
extremely common as a fighter so you
want to have a good amount of those so
we'll just go through the leveling here
and I'll show you the best choices to
make to make this the strongest version
of AEL at level two you get yourself the
action surge there which is really nice
to have uh is you need to sometimes just
hit a lot of things with your sword and
that's exactly what that'll help you do
now for our subass I really like to go
with the Battle Master the Elder snate
is another good build I do have a video
on that on my channel so you can check
that out but Battle Master is a Little
Bit Stronger cuz the elders KN focus on
throwing their weapon now for the
Maneuvers repost is the best one to go
with this is a reaction whenever an
enemy misses you can attack back and
deal an attack that does an additional
one8 damage so weaponizing your your
reaction is huge and something you
always want to do the next best one is
menacing attack which deals that one
additional 1d8 and possibly frightens
the target pushing attack can be nice to
push targets off of Ledges I don't
recommend sweep attack because it uses
your die 1d8 for attacks and another
great choice would be to go with the
distracting strike to give advantage on
the next attack roll against the Target
and disarming strike but I think
disarming strike is the best choice here
you can use the range one make an enemy
drop their weapon and then have someone
else pick it up and they become somewhat
useless now at level four we get
ourselves a feat and I think this is
best to go with an increase to our
constitution or to our strength so you
can increase one of these here
accordingly depending if you find you
need more health or more strength
although you can also use strength
potions if you want you can buy three of
them from ATI ethyl at the Grove so that
is another really useful option and if
you go that road alert is another good
feat if you want to use that and even
the Savage attacker which will roll your
damage dies another good one but not
great early on is the great weapon
master so whenever you land a critical
hit you can do another another attack as
a bonus action and attacks with weapons
your proficient in you can deal
additional 10 damage it cost of minus
five to attack rolls so we can take that
a little bit later on uh alerts another
good one for the
increased the increased initiative here
level five extra attack enough said
power Spike we can attack twice per turn
now and at level six we get ourselves
another feat which is incredible and we
can take ourselves a great weapon Master
here which again gives us initial 10 on
our attacks but minus five to attack
rolls so that's pretty fun we get
ourselves two more Maneuvers and another
die here I like rally grading at eight
temporary health points where this
becomes really useful is if you have a
teammate that went down you can use
rally to pick them back up in addition
to that you can also not have you can't
be counterspelled by this so with this
it has an 18 M range bonus action
whereas healing word can be counter
spelled this is huge making this a very
effective option we can also go with
distracting strike but I think pushing
attack here is a good one and also trip
attack not a Target prone but the
pushing attack to be able to push and
Target off of Ledges is extremely useful
so we'll go that route now level eight
we get ourselves another feat so you can
take the Savage attacker if you didn't
take the uh weapon Master perk here so
this allows you to roll your damage die
just flat out dealing more damage
Sharpshooter can be nice too if you want
to go with like a range spin on this as
well even heavy armor Master increase
your armor class you can also go with
the classic ability score Improvement to
take up your Constitution if you'd like
level 9 we get indomitable whenever we
fail a saving throw We Roll again so
higher chance succeeding on evading
Spells at level 10 we get ourselves the
improved combat superiority increasing
the die to a 1 d10 and we get two more
of these so we can take ourselves the
maneuver trip attack as well Precision
attack could be okay to spend a superior
die to add it to your attack roll so
this doesn't add damage I get a lot of
people commenting saying this is
actually damage but attack rolls are
your chance to hit so you can use it to
increase your hit chance maneuvering
attacks nice too cuz you can do the
additional damage on your attack and
then you can give half movement speed to
um to a target from this creature so
that's really useful if you need to get
someone else in a good position
maneuvering attacks actually pretty
useful goting attack is weird the
targets receive disadvantage on
attacking other creatures but they still
seem to attack other creatures I'm not
sure if that one's broken um I just
haven't had great experience with
goating attack and there's some mods
that fix it at level 11 we get our
improved extra attack this is a big
Power Spike again making this one of the
strongest offensive classes we can stay
level 12 and take the extra feed but I
actually think the best choice is to go
with the cleric now hear me out on this
we get a few cantrips which are fun just
to have like resistance and guidance can
be effective um not something we're
going to use often but you also got
different damaging can TRS that again
not something you really want to use so
something like light can be good to our
thur you get ADV advantage on
intimidation performance checks now for
our subass we're actually going to go
with the war domain why are we doing
this because we get War domain charges
allowing us to do bonus action attacks
three times which is is very useful for
our deity we can go with FL Ki I think
this is a little bit bugged oh we got it
there FL Ki the Lech Queen just fits
thematically and for a prepared spells
you can have create water set up your
teammates if you got a certain team
that's you know needs that healing work
can be okay command you won't hit ever
so Sanctuary is another nice one just
for defensive purposes um but if you
have a water team or anyone that deals
cold or lightning damage taking create
water can be a nice way to spend a
couple spell slots to help set up now
the true meaning of this is we we want
to go ahead with uh with the war domain
cleric we want to use our um War domain
charges to get those extra attacks per
long rest they can be nice sometimes you
just need an extra attack and that's
exactly what we can get with this now
for our gear early game the best armor
is the adamantine splint armor so wear
whatever handy armor until you can get
this armor cuz this is going to be the
best slot also gloves of dexterity to
put your dexterity to 18 is extremely
useful cuz this will increase your
overall initiative and this you can get
at the GI Yankee Crush so very early on
in the game bone Spike gloves will also
ignore resistances to slashing piercing
bludgeoning damage making it a very good
choice as well and also the hell dust
gloves can deal additional 1d6 of fire
damage so you can pick one of these that
you find works best for your character
armor persistence late gain best armor
decrease all uncoming damage by two you
gain resistance and blade Ward for half
physical damage and a 1 D4 bonus to are
saving throws so with this we have 23
Armor class I'm also using silver plane
the astral sword or astral silver sword
the astral plane this is a sword you can
get extremely early on if you want to
use command drop or honey on kith Voss
who was at act one before the mountain
pass when you get this weapon it does a
lot of damage when wielded by a gith
Yankee it deals an additional 1d6 of
psychic damage and get the Yankee
holding this as advantage on
intelligence wisdom and Charisma saving
throws resistance to psychic damage and
cannot be Charmed making them very
powerful however you got other gith
Yankee swords you can get early game
those would be the best choices late
game the baluran Giant Slayer is the
best choice the sh Spear of the evening
is great if you go for an evil route and
naona is also a very effective weapon CU
you get increased movement speed and you
can throw this and it'll return to your
hand so gives you a ranged option as
well I also like the Hellfire hand
crossbow n Mister but you can go with
gter male because this will give you
haste and if you're outside of Honor
mode you can get three attacks Hast
yourself three attacks and then action
surge three attacks War priest charge 10
attacks that is insane so that is my
preference there I also like the Ring of
free movement can't be train uh
difficult trained slow down can't be
paralyzed or restrained ring of
protection for increased Armor class
although you can also go with the kill
killer sweetheart for increased critical
hit chance amulet or greater health is
good in the end game however early game
the aberration Hunter a GI the Yankee
wear and this has advantaged on
intelligence saving throws and
aberration have disadvantaged on attack
rolls against us so this is useful when
fighting mine flares there are other
necklaces early game that you can go
with but it's kind of whatever you get
that's going to be probably your best
choice I also like the disintegrating
night walkers for early game boots but
I'm also going with the boots of Sonic
movement so whenever I get the Yankee
cast fly they're melee attack does 1 D4
of psychic damage so flying around is
great but uh yeah early game also go
with whatever bow that you find uh the
Titan string bow when using strength
potions can be useful with a strength
potion we got ourselves set up here uh
only 14 dexterity but with the the
gloves de area that puts it to an 18 27
strength 23 Constitution so we're pretty
strong we can take a lot of damage and
I'll show off what this will look like
in combat so if you know you're going to
get into a fight you can pre-buff
Yourself by increasing your jump
distance with the GI Yankee Sonic Jump
we got Missy step there for any bad
encounters that may happen we also get
the Mage hand here so you can use this
to throw health potions if you wanted to
like drop a potion for it and it can it
can throw them for you which is nice so
that is another I guess way to use this
so you go into your inventory drop the
potions on the ground your Mage hand
will sit there and it can pick them up
and throw them so another thing we want
to do is before we get into a fight we
want to apply the celestial haste to
oursel too so this can help with the
amount of damage we're going to do by
giving us extra actions so once you get
that going then you can start off combat
so I guess we'll go into turn base mode
and then just go in for the strike so we
got lots of different attacks here also
using the gith born flying boots can be
good because you can give yourself fly
and then get the additional psychic
damage which is a base weapon attack
there deals pretty good damage and U
let's get right into our fight so we got
one attack there it might be glitched
out yeah whenever you start at a fight
it removes one of your actions so
typically we would have had more
actions there but uh we're going to use
our second action for the three attacks
and then we also have some bonus
powerful attacks there if we need to um
and we also get the war priest charges
since we took out an enemy we also get
our great weapon Master bonus attack so
um we just go in and strike often so
there's another attack and then great
weapon master attack and uh we got a
critical hit Bonk that took them out
super useful so I'm not even going to
use that action surge right yet we'll
just go into to um just wait here to see
what happens and uh yeah we're just
going to let them come towards us they
use blade on us we saved on it cuz we
have indomitable oh there's two of them
right there perfect they're going to ins
snare me saved on it perfect
Constitution saving throw successful
Fighters have Constitution saving throw
uh and or proficiency so they get a plus
four to their saving throws meaning
we'll hold our haste more likely and uh
indomitable we almost got IND dominated
ah we got knocked out concentration
saving throw successful and then we're
back up here and uh now we're going to
lay down the law for what they did to us
we lost we lost our haste unfortunately
so we can't do the 10 attacks and for
that I'm going to make him pay with a
soul breaker but typically you would
also want to have your you would also
have a uh you'd want to have a sorcerer
with you so that you could deal
additional damage we stun them so we can
go after another Target and with this we
also have all of our um all of our extra
Battle Master Maneuvers so going with a
menacing strike range can be pretty
useful
we don't have The High Ground Advantage
here so that's not ideal but we can
Missy step and get closer or we can move
around cuz we stun them so uh we don't
have enough moving speed so we can just
go ahead here and get the jump on them
teleport behind them and they are none
the wiser so we can go ahead and go with
our menacing strike here if we want to
and uh that should do a good amount of
damage potentially we'll frighten them
and uh we got our hit off boom critical
hit perfect and uh they they got guiding
bolted so perfect and you don't even
have to follow up with another one but
we can go with a uh with a pushing
attack we want to knock them out of our
place so that can be useful too we can
see send him down to the lower ground
keep them away from us and uh we could
go with an action surge here to deal a
little bit extra damage so this is good
for when you have The High Ground
especially with the Missy St useful
we'll take them out and then we'll
finish it off by taking them out
hopefully but they're stunned so and we
got ourselves an extra attack too so boo
yeah using up the bonus action extra
attack can be kind of annoying so you
don't want to do that too too often
unfortunately we did lose our haste but
that would have gave us 10 attacks per
turn which is quite enough and uh yeah
we can also go with a pushing attack
again or we can go with a trip attack um
also the disarming attacks are pretty
fun so you can use these to I should
just use a normal Arrow there but that's
to got rid of his weapon and they'll
deal additional damage on these so those
are good weapon dropped they usually
pick it back up too and uh then we just
pick away you want to have The High
Ground if at all possible because using
your bow attacks for the 10 attacks can
be extremely useful they survive somehow
so we'll just let them do their thing we
should have probably moved out of the
acid and they use blade on us again but
we saved on it cuz we got
indomitable and uh they're throwing oh
there's another one coming at me there
throwing some sticks at me that is fine
because we got the ability to heal
ourselves and also rally if we need to
so
second wins a bonus action heal pretty
useful so we can go with that heal
ourselves and then U frighten our Target
with the arrows so we can use this to
hopefully frighten them boom critical
hit nice and then we'll move over here
take them out with our ranged attack and
then finalize them with a oh we won't be
able to make it to them but we just go
with another arrow attack and if you got
other types of arrows you can use
something like that for darkness which
is nice to set up my game's a little bit
I accidentally hit the floor
crap um but yeah they're frightened so
they aren't doing nothing and then we
can literally just go up to them and
give them the big old Bonk and uh great
weapon Master deals additional damage so
boom that took them out you can see the
fighter is quite strong the best way to
use the fighter is to get in get your
attacks in use your haste to give
yourself additional Armor class and
movement speed so you can run around if
you need to you also have guidance and
resistance to buff yourself and even
Divine favor for the increased damage if
you got the uhu I guess it's the war
cleric mod but uh Sanctuary is also nice
too you apply to yourself and then
you're safe so even if you don't attack
it's uh just there for survivability
sake but yeah that is the most OP LEL
build keeping it lore friendly as well
she's a Battle Master fighter Elder
Knight works as well too but you'd want
to take inside the cleric take a level
of wizard describe spells so let me know
your thoughts in the comments below
thank you so much for watching and I'll
see you all in the next video hit the
Subscribe button below if you haven't
already